Shcherbak Aleksei | PHP Developer

Creative PHP (Laravel) Developer with 4+ years of strong experience in backend (PHP, Laravel, C#, .NET) and frontend (vue, jQuery), GOF Design Patterns & OOP areas with willingness to learn new technologies and languages like Golang or Python.

CONTACTS

• **Phone**: +7-911-911-4396

• Email: aleksej.shherbak@yandex.ru

• LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/aleksej-shherbak-538914165/

KEY SKILLS

Back End:

• PHP: 5, 7, 8

• C# (as an additional language)

Front End:

- Vue, CSS, HTML
- JavaScript, ES6, REST
- jQuery, Bootstrap

Databases:

- MySQL
- Postgres

Testing:

• PHPUnit, TDD

DevOps:

• Familiar with Gitlab CI, Jenkins, Github actions, Azure devops

Additional instruments:

• Git, Rest, xDebug, Docker / docker-compose

SDLC:

• BRD, GoF Design Patterns, OOP

WORK HISTORY

Quantum Art, Backend Developer, September 2020 - till now

https://quantumart.ru

- Conducting requirements gathering and validation as a part of collaboration for the critical parts of a big telecom operator's website.
- Developing new and customization of the existing features (backend 80%, frontend 20%) for the high-volume telecom operator website.
- Documenting implemented features.
- Assessing project requirements using Agile & Scrum principles related to the critical parts of a big telecom operator's website resulting in estimation of Level of effort and required working hours.

PushApp, Backend Developer, Fullstack Developer, August 2018 — June 2020

https://pushapp.ru

- Maintaining newly developed and legacy systems critical internal web application utilizing PHP, Laravel, Codeigniter, JavaScript and ES6, jQuery.
- Designing new databases and data schemas for the business-critical online service improving data integrity and execution efficiency.
- Creating new web applications from scratch
- Full Stack development of the high-volume analytical-facing web application applying knowledge of Vue/Vuex and Rest.
- Performance tunning of the legacy data storages.
- Mentoring and couching newly hired team members.

Blackidea, Fullstack Developer, Fullstack Developer, December 2017 — June 2018

- Full Stack development of the high-volume eCommerce website using PHP and Bitrix framework.
- Developing web applications from scratch using the company's own architecture PHP boilerplate.

Seventest, Backend Developer (intern), Backend Developer, February 2015 —June 2015

http://seventest.ru/

• Support legacy web-application using LAMP stack and Drupal 6.

PROJECTS

- https://pushapp.ru (creating own CMS using Laravel)
- https://payforinstall.ru (maintains critical features using Codeigniter)

- https://new.rodovoederevo.ru/ (implementing different backend features and background tasks using .NET Core 3.1 and C#)
- https://mts.ru (Maintaining legacy parts of the website, creating new features according to business demands)
- https://skylink.ru (Support and customization of the existing features)

EDUCATION

• St. Petersburg State University of Telecommunications named after Prof. M.A. Bonch-Bruevich 2018

MY STRENGTHS

I do not shift my job to someone else. If I have a problem, and I can't solve it, at the same time, I know that one of my colleagues is unlikely to answer me right away, I'd better go to Stackoverflow and ask there. In addition to programming, I like music, play guitar in a band. I try to develop comprehensively and not be a "troglodyte", shielded from the outside world by a wall of monitors.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- $\bullet~$ English language: B2
- Ready to relocation